

ASHIBUR RAHMAN (PRINCE)

+8801614994249

ashiburprince@gmail.com 256/2 Index Aurora, Tajlane, Mirpur, Dhaka-1216

Skills

Testing

Manual Testing including different testing techniques, DB testing, QA Automation using Cypress, Selenium & Playwright. API testing using SOAPUI & Postman.

Project Management

Project management software (Jira), Git Repositories Zenhub, SDLC, STLC, Documentation, Microsoft Office (Excel, Word, PowerPoint), Agile (Scrum) Methodologies, Problem-Solving.

Development

Java (Basic), JavaScript (Basic), TypeScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Jquery.

Design

Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe XD.

Profile

A process focused on technical expertise and considerable software development experience. Get what makes technology efforts successful with **over 4 years** as an **SQA Engineer**, doing both Automation & Manual testing and support expertise. Experience in manual and automation testing (Cypress with Cucumber, Selenium & Playwright) for financial and different Enterprise applications. Excellent knowledge of Software development and Project management, testing life cycles, SQA methodology, and test process documentation.

Experience

City Bank PLC. | SQA Engineer (Officer, IT)

(January 2024 - Present)

- The role involves reviewing BRD and FSD, understanding business requirements, Create Test Case, conducting UAT with business, project management, DB testing, prioritizing products, collaborating with developers, analyzing root causes, preparing observation reports, tracking bugs, API testing using SOAPUI. Doing Automation testing using Java & Selenium in multiple financial application. Also implemented Playwright in an enterprise application.
- Application: LWF, Fin-Tech, Bancassurance, Capital Market Management System, CCVR, Bulk A Challan, Cliental Service Management, Customer Service Portal, QR Merchant Portal, FCY Liquidity Management, Locker Module, City Live.
- Tools: Toad for Oracle, Swagger, JIRA, SOAPUI, Postman, Playwright, Selenium, JMeter, Mantis.

Gain Solutions | SQA Automation Engineer

(March 2023 – December 2023)

- The position entails evaluating designs, business support, basic CRUD DB test, translating technical specifications into test cases, and creating bug reports. It involves working with development and SQA teams, testing new features, creating new issues on JIRA and Zenhub boards, monitoring website functionality, executing automation testing using Cypress, maintaining Agile methodologies, and performing load and performance testing using Apache JMeter and Postman.
- Application: CRM, HRM, SFA, E-Commerce site (www.uniteliving.com)
- Tools: Cypress, Cucumber, My SQL, Postman, JMeter, Zenhub, JIRA, Excel.

Cycas IT | SQA Engineer

(March 2021 – February 2023)

- Managed a company project, discussed bug fixes with the Development Team, executed test cases, and developed comprehensive test reports. They ensured stakeholder satisfaction and managed deployment deliverables. They identified and minimized risks, maintained the software solution, prioritized tasks, and used technical knowledge to solve problems and release them faster.
- Application: ERP (E-Commerce), HRM.
- Tools: Cypress, Cucumber, Postman, JMeter, JIRA, Excel.

Education

M.Sc. in CSE

Jahangirnagar University (2021-2022)

CGPA: 3.20 Out of (4.00)

B.Sc. in CSE

Daffodil International University (2017-2021)

CGPA: 3.71 Out of (4.00)

H.S.C

Milestone College (2015)

CGPA: 4.92 Out of (5.00)

S.S.C

Sarail Annada Govt. High School (2013)

CGPA: 5 Out of (5.00)

Interests

- Traveling
- Researching
- Playing Cricket
- Playing Badminton
- Riding Bike
- Watching Movies

Course & Certification

- Successfully completed 'Banking Foundation Program' from City Bank PLC.
- Certification on 'Secured Programming for Secured Web Application' from City Bank PLC. Organized by ICT TAG.
- Successfully completed 'Universal Pension Scheme' from City Bank PLC.
- SQA (Manual & Automation Testing) at IT Training BD.
- Participated in the DIU AUPF-2019 program Protocol Team to warmly welcome the international delegates.
- Participated ICPC Regional Programming Contest.

Achievement

- Best Performer of the Year-2024 By EA
 IT Division, City Bank PLC.
- Reward & Recognition for implementing Automation Testing in a Corporate Banking Project at City Bank PLC.
- R&R Projects: Bancassurance, Capital Market, Cliental Service Management.
- Event Organizer
 City Bank IT (Team
 Collaboration)
- Recognized as the Employee of the Month (July, August) at Gain Solutions Ltd.

References

Prof. Dr. Touhid Bhuiyan

Professor & Head Dept. of C.S.E. Daffodil International University +880 1847140016 headcse@daffodilvarsity.edu.bd

Manik Sanyal

Senior Manager & AVP
Payments & Back Office Systems
Information Technology
City Bank PLC.
+88 01718 225895
manik.sanyal@thecitybank.com